<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>OSR on The ChaosGrenade</title>
    <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/tags/osr/</link>
    <description>Recent content in OSR on The ChaosGrenade</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 19:33:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://chaosgrenade.com/tags/osr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>FABRICATED VENTURERS — a Classless Hack for Vieja Escuela</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-07-25-fabricated-venturers-a-classless-hack-for-vieja-escuela/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 19:33:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-07-25-fabricated-venturers-a-classless-hack-for-vieja-escuela/</guid>
      <description>I have written a classless, patchwork/piecemeal character hack for Vieja Escuela. Taking advantage of the format of VE: Pamphlet Edition, it’s written as a modular variant to the Character Creation rules. Just swap out and use without changing the rest of the game! Or you can just print out, fold up, and tuck it in your original VE rulebook.
The Concept Fabricated Venturers ditches classes. Everyone starts as a d6 hit die character, proficient in simple weapons and Leather armor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VIEJA ESCUELA: Pamphlet Edition</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-06-28-vieja-escuela-pamphlet-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 21:07:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-06-28-vieja-escuela-pamphlet-edition/</guid>
      <description>I have taken the core rules of Vieja Escuela (which I’ve praised on herebefore) and repackaged it. As the name implies, this version is intended to be printed out and folded into three “zig-zag” or “accordion” style pamphlets (Character Creation, Game Rules, &amp;amp; Tables). Of course, it also looks good on tablets, or printed out and left on their own. Do whatever pleases you! This was a first time project for me using Affinity Publisher, and I’m pretty happy to share the results!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ATHAS: DARK SUN, DESERT PLANET (SB&amp;CS)</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-04-29-athas-dark-sun-desert-planet-sbcs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 15:15:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-04-29-athas-dark-sun-desert-planet-sbcs/</guid>
      <description>Filed Under: Campaign Ideas I Need Out of My Head.
Premise: The Dark Sun setting re-imagined for the space fantasy game Solar Blades &amp;amp; Cosmic Spells.
Other Influences: Dune, Heavy Metal, and the artwork of Moebius.
Preface: I really love Dark Sun on the surface. The core AD&amp;amp;D 2e boxset did a great job setting up the world of Athas and showing the “world at a glance” so to speak. The places where I start to tune out is when it essentially shoe-horns D&amp;amp;Disms into its unique setting, and the metaplot of events didn’t really impress me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rambling On: Solar Blades &amp; Cosmic Spells</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-03-05-rambling-on-solar-blades-cosmic-spells/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 16:05:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-03-05-rambling-on-solar-blades-cosmic-spells/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been a hell of a wait, but at long last I have Diogo Nogueira’s latest offering: &lt;strong&gt;Solar Blades &amp;amp; Cosmic Spells.&lt;/strong&gt; Built off the same rules as his sword &amp;amp; sorcery offering &lt;em&gt;(Sharp Swords &amp;amp; Sinister Spells),&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;SB&amp;amp;CS&lt;/strong&gt; is more than a science-fantasy re-skin — it is a &lt;em&gt;massive&lt;/em&gt; offering of everything you would want or need for a gonzo, pulpy space adventure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rambling on: Vieja Escuela</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-01-20-rambling-on-vieja-escuela/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 18:08:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-01-20-rambling-on-vieja-escuela/</guid>
      <description>I’m mad at myself for not blogging about this until now. In the past year or so we’ve seen a lot of cool minimalist and “OSR-Adjacent” D&amp;amp;D clones come out. Black Hack 2e, Untold Adventures, and Knave are a few of the ones I enjoy. But the one that stole the show is a little booklet named Vieja Escuela, a Spanish RPG that had been translated to several languages (including English).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Plant Hack: Mutant Plants for The Rad Hack</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2017-05-11-the-plant-hack-mutant-plants-for-the-rad-hack/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2017 18:41:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2017-05-11-the-plant-hack-mutant-plants-for-the-rad-hack/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Mutant class in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.drivethrurpg.com/product/187874/The-RadHack&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Rad Hack&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is pretty flexible — you can easily be a mutant animal, plant, or some other strange humanoid. Still, I’ve had friends, followers, and even my spouse talk about how they wished the “Mutant Plant” was a class on its own. I decided to homebrew my own variant Plant class by re-skinning powers that already existed in the game. Enjoy!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GUTTERPUNK SESSION 2: “Come to Zom Zom’s — a Place to Eat!”</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2017-04-23-gutterpunk-session-2-come-to-zom-zoms-a-place-to-eat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2017 18:28:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2017-04-23-gutterpunk-session-2-come-to-zom-zoms-a-place-to-eat/</guid>
      <description>_This is a play report for **Gutterpunk Sprawl-Crawl, **a play-by-post campaign using **The Rad Hack. **This setting entails violence, drug use, and depraved morals — consider this your NSFW warning. _
When we left off last session, Leper Prawn and Absolvo had made it out alive from the radioactive sewers and have emerged about a block away from **Zom Zom’s, **a notorious restaurant that is a hub for all sorts of mutants, nomads, and biker gangs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gutterpunk Session 1: Down In It</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2017-04-05-gutterpunk-session-1-down-in-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 23:23:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2017-04-05-gutterpunk-session-1-down-in-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is the first play report of **&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Gutterpunk Sprawl Crawl&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;, **a gonzo urban setting using &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;The Rad Hack&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;. Crude language ahead — consider this your NSFW warning.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gutterpunk Sprawl Crawl: Setting Stuff</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2017-03-29-gutterpunk-sprawl-crawl-setting-stuff/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 22:19:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2017-03-29-gutterpunk-sprawl-crawl-setting-stuff/</guid>
      <description>Warning: Harsh NSFW Language Ahead
I recently began work on an obscene sandbox that primarily uses **The Rad Hack **but also borrows from other titles like Cyber Hacked, Augmented Reality, Other Dust and any thematically appropriate stuff I find in the OSR community.
I’ve actually begun running it as a Play-by-Post via a private Facebook Group. This format actually works well because it means I can troll Google Images for inspirational artwork to every scene and character, and we also keep an “Out of Character” chat open in messenger for “table talk” moments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Witch of the Citrine Tower</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2017-02-09-the-witch-of-the-citrine-tower/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 22:31:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2017-02-09-the-witch-of-the-citrine-tower/</guid>
      <description>_This post is some raw ideas transcribed from some very loose notes from a one-shot adventure I put together for **Swords &amp;amp; Wizardry. **__I present them here as a loose framework for anyone to use however they wish in their own games. _
The immediate area surrounding the town of Silverbrooke has long been protected by the “witch” of the Citrine Tower. Though human, she’s been around as long as a lot of elves can remember.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[WHITE STAR]: 5 Quick &amp; Dirty Supplement Reviews</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2015-06-15-white-star-5-quick-dirty-supplement-reviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 01:41:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2015-06-15-white-star-5-quick-dirty-supplement-reviews/</guid>
      <description>Today’s post is looking at five different supplements available from RPGNow, each of them no more than a few bucks. I’ve been enjoying the hell out of **White Star. **And one of the solid strengths of it is the amazing community and third-party support that is running with it.
Psionics **Author: **Matthew Skail
**Cost: **$1.99
**Page Count: **11 (including cover and license)
_Psionics _is what it says on the tin: a psionicist class for White Star.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WHITE STAR: A Rambling Review</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2015-05-29-white-star-a-rambling-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2015 05:38:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2015-05-29-white-star-a-rambling-review/</guid>
      <description>I have a curse where every time I say “I don’t need another OSR game!” I open up my wallet and acquire another one.
**White Star **is written by James M. Spahn and released by Barrel Rider Games. The gist of it is they took the rules from Swords &amp;amp; Wizardry Whitebox and hacked it into their own super slick science fiction game. Now, I’m already a rabid fan of Kevin Crawford’s _Stars Without Number, _and I was hesitant to toss $10 at a lighter, simpler game.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
