<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gonzo Mutoids on The ChaosGrenade</title>
    <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/tags/gonzo-mutoids/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gonzo Mutoids on The ChaosGrenade</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 01:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://chaosgrenade.com/tags/gonzo-mutoids/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Gonzo Mutoids -- Pocket Edition!</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-10-17-gonzo-mutoids-pocket/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-10-17-gonzo-mutoids-pocket/</guid>
      <description>PURCHASE ON ITCH
My love letter to bat-shit crazy, kitchen sink, post apocalyptic settings is now available as a tiny pocket RPG &amp;ndash; this time powered by TRICUBE TALES! All you need is three six-sided dice, some spare tokens and scratch paper.
The base game consists of two tiny booklets (the core game, as well as a bonus GM booklet) that you may print out and fold using the Pocketfold method.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DRIVE·10 MOCKUPS: GONZO MUTOIDS</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-04-11-drive10-mockups-gonzo-mutoids/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 15:02:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-04-11-drive10-mockups-gonzo-mutoids/</guid>
      <description>Much like the Dungeon Delvers mock up, this post provides a few GONZO MUTOID WASTELAND CRUST PUNKS characters that you can either use as pre-gens, NPCs, or just inspiration for building your own.
Radjak, a Shifty Telepathic Bug Scoundrel. Radjak is a typical rogue you’d find gambling in any post-Frag trade hub. He likes using his telepathy during games of Globwox Hold ‘Em. His strategy isn’t just to sense who may have the better hand, but to pick up on other cheaters so he can try to call their shenanigans out before anyone suspects him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GONZO MUTOID WASTELAND CRUST PUNKS HAS RETURNED!</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-04-08-gonzo-mutoid-wasteland-crust-punks-has-returned/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 15:30:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-04-08-gonzo-mutoid-wasteland-crust-punks-has-returned/</guid>
      <description>The crazy, zany, bat-shit insane post-apocalyptic project that triggered the creation of Drive·10 has now finally glued itself back together! GONZO MUTOID WASTELAND CRUST PUNKS is now available to everyone who pays $2+ to support D·10 on Itch. Inspired by RIFTS, Gamma World, TMNT, Rick &amp;amp; Morty, Adventure Time, Heavy Metal, Super Jail and all sorts of other junk I like, GMWCP is an attempt at a rules-lite game of a fractured reality.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
