<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Osprey on The ChaosGrenade</title>
    <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/tags/osprey/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Osprey on The ChaosGrenade</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 08:00:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://chaosgrenade.com/tags/osprey/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Released: SIGIL &amp; SHADOW</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-7-22-sigil-and-shadow-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 08:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-7-22-sigil-and-shadow-release/</guid>
      <description>The invocation is complete – the key to my nightmares, made manifest and in my hands. Sigil &amp;amp; Shadow has been years in the works. So many gaming sessions. Years of feedback. Lots of caffeine, bad food decisions, late night drives, music play lists, awkward hours spent trying not to wake up my child, two fucking presidential elections and surviving a pandemic have gone into making this. Finally, it’s a finished dream; a physical artifact that I can touch and pass off to you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pulling Back the Curtain (on Sigil &amp; Shadow)</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-2-16-pulling-back-the-curtain/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 12:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-2-16-pulling-back-the-curtain/</guid>
      <description>Out Now!
Ghosts. Vampires. The monster in your closet. The bogeyman under your bed. The cryptid you read about online. They’re all real. They lurk in our shadows. They linger in our reflections. Good people make pacts with demons they find online. Creatures from beyond time prowl the city streets. Forgotten rituals are reborn as viral memes. The rich and powerful consort with ancient beings behind boardroom doors. Entities beyond our comprehension exploit our desires, gorge themselves on our fears, and manifest as our nightmares.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[UPDATE] SIGIL &amp; SHADOW</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2020-06-17-update-sigil-shadow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 15:46:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2020-06-17-update-sigil-shadow/</guid>
      <description>Looks like Amazon UK has let the cat out of the bag:
SIGIL &amp;amp; SHADOW: A Roleplaying Game of Urban Fantasy and Occult Horror is due out next year from Osprey Games. I’ve been really excited to be among the next wave of their RPG releases — you can expect some upcoming rambles about Romance of the Perilous Land and Paleomythic.
For now, though, I felt an up-to-date post about where S&amp;amp;S is in 2020 is important; especially since the Amazon listing has resulted in lots of traffic at older posts from 2014-2015.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
