<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Highland Paranormal on The ChaosGrenade</title>
    <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/tags/highland-paranormal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Highland Paranormal on The ChaosGrenade</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 15:50:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://chaosgrenade.com/tags/highland-paranormal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>SHROOM GOONS Update!</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-09-26-shroom-goons-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 15:50:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-09-26-shroom-goons-update/</guid>
      <description>Some big news regarding SHROOM GOONS!
First off, we got third place in the Goon Jam on Itch.io! Thanks to everyone who’s supported this little title and left amazing feedback and reviews. And to the person who left a 1 star without comment — why do you hate fun?
Second off, there is now an updated SHROOM GOONS available on Itch! Minor edits, small clarifications, expanded Difficulty Scores, and a Referee section that offers some ways to tweak and handle difficult encounters &amp;amp; challenges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SHROOM GOONS — A New Free Title!</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-08-20-shroom-goons-a-new-free-title/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 15:08:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-08-20-shroom-goons-a-new-free-title/</guid>
      <description>SHROOM GOONS is a “Spore-Core” Fantasy Trip for Weird People. A hack of Nate Treme’s Tunnel Goons , players take on the role of tiny mushroom folk on a big adventure! Inspired by Fragglerock, Smurfs, The Littles, Toy Story and other childhood “tiny people” stories. It’s weird, it’s fun, it’s easy to pick up and play. And it features artwork by Skullfungus!
 Arm yourself with a sewing needle sword, a button shield, and ready your matchstick torch!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rambling on: In The Light of a Ghost Star</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-01-29-rambling-on-in-the-light-of-a-ghost-star/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 16:59:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-01-29-rambling-on-in-the-light-of-a-ghost-star/</guid>
      <description>Short, sweet, and to the point: **In The Light of a Ghost Star **by Nate Treme of Highland Paranormal Society is a wonderful zine-rpg that is easy to pick up and run after a quick read through. Players take on the role of martian explorers being dropped off on a dead Earth to explore its treacherous ruins filled with strange inhabitants. That’s literally all the story we have, and it’s all that’s really needed.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
