<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>fan stuff on The ChaosGrenade</title>
    <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/categories/fan-stuff/</link>
    <description>Recent content in fan stuff on The ChaosGrenade</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 19:33:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://chaosgrenade.com/categories/fan-stuff/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>FABRICATED VENTURERS — a Classless Hack for Vieja Escuela</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-07-25-fabricated-venturers-a-classless-hack-for-vieja-escuela/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 19:33:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-07-25-fabricated-venturers-a-classless-hack-for-vieja-escuela/</guid>
      <description>I have written a classless, patchwork/piecemeal character hack for Vieja Escuela. Taking advantage of the format of VE: Pamphlet Edition, it’s written as a modular variant to the Character Creation rules. Just swap out and use without changing the rest of the game! Or you can just print out, fold up, and tuck it in your original VE rulebook.
The Concept Fabricated Venturers ditches classes. Everyone starts as a d6 hit die character, proficient in simple weapons and Leather armor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VIEJA ESCUELA: Pamphlet Edition</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-06-28-vieja-escuela-pamphlet-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 21:07:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-06-28-vieja-escuela-pamphlet-edition/</guid>
      <description>I have taken the core rules of Vieja Escuela (which I’ve praised on herebefore) and repackaged it. As the name implies, this version is intended to be printed out and folded into three “zig-zag” or “accordion” style pamphlets (Character Creation, Game Rules, &amp;amp; Tables). Of course, it also looks good on tablets, or printed out and left on their own. Do whatever pleases you! This was a first time project for me using Affinity Publisher, and I’m pretty happy to share the results!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Plant Hack: Mutant Plants for The Rad Hack</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2017-05-11-the-plant-hack-mutant-plants-for-the-rad-hack/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2017 18:41:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2017-05-11-the-plant-hack-mutant-plants-for-the-rad-hack/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Mutant class in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.drivethrurpg.com/product/187874/The-RadHack&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Rad Hack&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is pretty flexible — you can easily be a mutant animal, plant, or some other strange humanoid. Still, I’ve had friends, followers, and even my spouse talk about how they wished the “Mutant Plant” was a class on its own. I decided to homebrew my own variant Plant class by re-skinning powers that already existed in the game. Enjoy!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SHADOW OPS</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2015-05-06-shadow-ops/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2015 21:16:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2015-05-06-shadow-ops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shadow Ops: Covert Ops in the Sixth World&lt;/strong&gt; is a fan tribute to the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Shadowrun&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; franchise, using a mash-up of Covert Ops and BareBones Fantasy by &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;DwD Studios.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; Inspired by the streamlined mechanics and tactical play of the PC games in particular, it only seemed fitting to mix one of the biggest and best settings in the RPG industry with the fast-playing d00Lite system.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mashed-Up: The Strange, Accelerated.</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2015-04-13-mashed-up-the-strange-accelerated/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2015 13:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2015-04-13-mashed-up-the-strange-accelerated/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What follows is a set of house rules I originally came up with to run&lt;a href=&#34;http://thestrangerpg.com/&#34;&gt;The Strange&lt;/a&gt; by Monte Cook Games using &lt;strong&gt;Fate Accelerated&lt;/strong&gt; by Evil Hat Studios. At the time, I wasn’t too sure how I felt about the Cypher System. Since then, I’ve ran quite a few games using both The Strange and the &lt;strong&gt;Cypher System Rulebook.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s grown on me, and it’s one of my favorite new systems.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
