<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sigil and shadow on The ChaosGrenade</title>
    <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/tags/sigil-and-shadow/</link>
    <description>Recent content in sigil and shadow on The ChaosGrenade</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 13:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://chaosgrenade.com/tags/sigil-and-shadow/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>[SIGIL &amp; SHADOW] Factions &amp; Stature</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2022-3-04-faction-stature/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2022-3-04-faction-stature/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Header Art by Luis F. Sanz&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://chaosgrenade.com/page/sigil-and-shadow/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sigil &amp;amp; Shadow&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; strives to cover the tropes of urban fantasy and modern horror &amp;ndash; hunting down monstrous threats, investigating paranormal mysteries, researching hidden magic and communing with powerful entities.  But it also allows players to &lt;em&gt;become&lt;/em&gt; monstrous individuals, treading down paths of power that often put them at odds with both the cities they live in and the others who haunt its streets. While &amp;ldquo;Scooby gang mysteries&amp;rdquo; are a staple of the genre, so to are stories of ancient feuds, dark conspiracies, and rivalries that litter the streets with blood and fire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today we&amp;rsquo;re taking a dive into using &lt;strong&gt;factions&lt;/strong&gt; as part of a Sigil &amp;amp; Shadow campaign.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[SIGIL &amp; SHADOW] Invoking the Fanbase</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2022-2-22-invoking-the-fanbase/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2022-2-22-invoking-the-fanbase/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Header Art by Luis F. Sanz&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First off, apologies for the delay on anything new regarding Sigil &amp;amp; Shadow.&lt;br&gt;
While I&amp;rsquo;ve been distracted trying to get my act together going forward in 2022, some really cool peeps have put together some handy stuff for Sigil &amp;amp; Shadow!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mud &amp; Blood: SIGIL &amp; SHADOW Actual Play!</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-11-01-mud-and-blood/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-11-01-mud-and-blood/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was honored to have the chance to run &lt;strong&gt;SIGIL &amp;amp; SHADOW&lt;/strong&gt; for the Mud &amp;amp; Blood podcast&amp;rsquo;s Halloween Special! Just a fun note: this episode essentially counts as Part 5 of &lt;a href=&#34;https://chaosgrenade.com/tags/wythe/&#34;&gt;The Wythe Case&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[SIGIL &amp; SHADOW] Resources</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-10-19-sigil-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-10-19-sigil-resources/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post will be constantly updated with useful documents, play aids and character sheets for &lt;strong&gt;Sigil &amp;amp; Shadow&lt;/strong&gt; as they become available. Check back often, and feel free to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:thechaosgrenade@gmail.com&#34;&gt;email me&lt;/a&gt; any cool homebrewed content you wish to share.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wythe Case, Part 4: A Shattered Nightmare</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-9-26-wythe-case-part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-9-26-wythe-case-part-4/</guid>
      <description>The entity paralyzing Samantha pays no attention to Julia, continuing to attempt to suffocate her with a swarm of shadowy bugs that bleed out from its outstretched hands. Julia hurriedly gestures her spell and screams &amp;ldquo;By my will, I demand you be banished from this place!&amp;rdquo; In a flash, ghostly arms wisp out and grab the horror, dragging it into the mirror as it howls in anguish. Julia rushes to Samantha&amp;rsquo;s side as she finally wakes up, sitting straight up and screaming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wythe Case, Part 3: Dead End Friends</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-9-26-wythe-case-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-9-26-wythe-case-part-3/</guid>
      <description>Samantha couldn&amp;rsquo;t sleep the nights following her encounter at the Wythe Estate. Any time she closed her eyes, that wretched man-bug with the hollowed eyes was there&amp;hellip; its severed and inhuman teeth. When she was awake, especially on the nights following, something else was there.
It hid in plain sight &amp;ndash; even when she meditated and gazed across the curtain into the Echo, it was only there the edges of the periphery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wythe Case, Part 2: Fight or Flight</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-9-21-wythe-case-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-9-21-wythe-case-part-2/</guid>
      <description>This narrative is a continuing example of gameplay for Sigil &amp;amp; Shadow, my role-playing game of Urban Fantasy &amp;amp; Occult Horror. We left Samantha Cane being pursued by some kind of gnarly half-humanoid, half-insect monstrosity chasing her out of an abandoned estate.
 You can catch up on part one here You can also check out Samantha Cane&amp;rsquo;s Character Sheet Learn more about Sigil &amp;amp; Shadow here   Our Story Continues Samantha runs out into dark night, sliding in the mud and frantically trying to find an escape from the Wythe estate grounds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wythe Case, Part 1: Break In</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-9-17-wythe-case-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-9-17-wythe-case-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Samantha Cane exits her ride, tips the driver, and proceeds to walk down the wet street towards the Wythe estate. Myrtle and Benjamin Wythe, as the local stories tell, were a couple found mutilated and murdered in their upper-end mansion back in the 1980s. They were pillars of the community — he was a business owner and once city council member; she was active in the PTA and their church. Both were found in their living room, tongues cut out and their hearts removed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Sigil &amp; Shadow] Julia Grave, Shadowed Occultist</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-9-5-julia-grave/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-9-5-julia-grave/</guid>
      <description>This is Part 2 of a series showing game play examples for Sigil &amp;amp; Shadow. You can read Part 1 here.
Today we&amp;rsquo;re having a look at a sample Shadowed character. These are the monstrous characters of our game, having embraced a darker side of them in exchange for paranormal power. Instead of defining how every vampire, werewolf, zombie or other thing that goes bump in the night works, we&amp;rsquo;ve established four broad courts of shadow &amp;ndash; the Ravenous, the Devoted, the Afflicted and the Hosts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Sigil &amp; Shadow] Seeking Samantha Cane</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-8-22-seeking-samantha-cane/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 08:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-8-22-seeking-samantha-cane/</guid>
      <description>This is the first part in a series of blogs that with the hopes of being walkthrough examples for Sigil &amp;amp; Shadow. Future posts will show sample gameplay concepts, but for today we&amp;rsquo;ll start out with some character creation. Let&amp;rsquo;s meet Samantha Cane, a woman in her late twenties who is obsessed with the supernatural.
If you haven&amp;rsquo;t picked up a copy yet, I recommend first checking out my previews at the Osprey Games Blog so some of these terms make sense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Released: SIGIL &amp; SHADOW</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-7-22-sigil-and-shadow-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 08:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-7-22-sigil-and-shadow-release/</guid>
      <description>The invocation is complete – the key to my nightmares, made manifest and in my hands. Sigil &amp;amp; Shadow has been years in the works. So many gaming sessions. Years of feedback. Lots of caffeine, bad food decisions, late night drives, music play lists, awkward hours spent trying not to wake up my child, two fucking presidential elections and surviving a pandemic have gone into making this. Finally, it’s a finished dream; a physical artifact that I can touch and pass off to you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pulling Back the Curtain (on Sigil &amp; Shadow)</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-2-16-pulling-back-the-curtain/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 12:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-2-16-pulling-back-the-curtain/</guid>
      <description>Out Now!
Ghosts. Vampires. The monster in your closet. The bogeyman under your bed. The cryptid you read about online. They’re all real. They lurk in our shadows. They linger in our reflections. Good people make pacts with demons they find online. Creatures from beyond time prowl the city streets. Forgotten rituals are reborn as viral memes. The rich and powerful consort with ancient beings behind boardroom doors. Entities beyond our comprehension exploit our desires, gorge themselves on our fears, and manifest as our nightmares.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[UPDATE] SIGIL &amp; SHADOW</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2020-06-17-update-sigil-shadow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 15:46:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2020-06-17-update-sigil-shadow/</guid>
      <description>Looks like Amazon UK has let the cat out of the bag:
SIGIL &amp;amp; SHADOW: A Roleplaying Game of Urban Fantasy and Occult Horror is due out next year from Osprey Games. I’ve been really excited to be among the next wave of their RPG releases — you can expect some upcoming rambles about Romance of the Perilous Land and Paleomythic.
For now, though, I felt an up-to-date post about where S&amp;amp;S is in 2020 is important; especially since the Amazon listing has resulted in lots of traffic at older posts from 2014-2015.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
