<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shadowrun on The ChaosGrenade</title>
    <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/tags/shadowrun/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Shadowrun on The ChaosGrenade</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 21:15:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://chaosgrenade.com/tags/shadowrun/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting Anarchy</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-05-13-fanstuff-revisiting-anarchy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 21:15:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-05-13-fanstuff-revisiting-anarchy/</guid>
      <description>Shadowrun: Anarchy is a title that I often call a “flawed gem” — a great game marred by poor execution. Rushed edits, a somewhat schizophrenic design (is it a core rulebook? Is it a supplement?), stretching itself thin trying to please both traditional SR veterans and newcomer storygamers. But despite all of that, underneath the rubble you can find the chassis of a slick, streamlined and adaptable dicepool system.
While I’m excited to see where the Sixth World Edition is heading, I find myself slinking back into my copy of Anarchy (goblinized warts and all).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ramblings on Shadowrun: Anarchy</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2016-10-17-ramblings-on-shadowrun-anarchy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 13:57:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2016-10-17-ramblings-on-shadowrun-anarchy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, it happened.&lt;br&gt;
Catalyst Game Labs released &lt;em&gt;**&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.drivethrurpg.com/product/194759/Shadowrun-Anarchy?hot60=0&amp;amp;src=hnum&#34;&gt;Shadowrun: Anarchy,&lt;/a&gt; **&lt;/em&gt; an “alternate rules set” that aims at letting players run the shadows of the Sixth World in a more story-driven rules set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking for a solid, full review of &lt;em&gt;Anarchy&lt;/em&gt; I highly recommend the &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Casting Shadows review.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;  Otherwise, I’m just going to sit here and gush fanboy for a moment…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SHADOW OPS: Street Samurai</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2015-05-07-shadow-ops-street-samurai/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2015 15:39:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2015-05-07-shadow-ops-street-samurai/</guid>
      <description>Oh man, the Street Samurai.
Years before I would know who Molly Millions was, I was a dorky 9 year old kid who laughed when my dad referred to my older brother’s weekend pastime as “Dungeons &amp;amp; Dumbass.” But then one Saturday morning, my brother had left out a book he borrowed from a friend. A book with a hot elf chick on the cover in cut off jeans, a book filled with gritty sci-fi urban landscapes, tribal shamans, and fantasy characters with electrodes plugged into their skull.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SHADOW OPS: Elven Adept</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2015-05-06-shadow-ops-elven-adept/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 20:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2015-05-06-shadow-ops-elven-adept/</guid>
      <description>So, after playing **Shadowrun Chronicles: Boston Lockdown **a bunch this week with Tim Kirk (of Silverlion Studios), I was inspired to whip-up **SHADOW OPS: Covert Ops in the Sixth World. **It’s a fan tribute to the Shadowrun franchise, inspired by the gameplay of the recent PC games using a mash-up of COVERT OPS and BareBones Fantasy from DwD Studios. I’m pretty happy with what I threw together between studying for finals, and the initial reactions from the BBF Community on G+ have been stellar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SHADOW OPS</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2015-05-06-shadow-ops/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2015 21:16:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2015-05-06-shadow-ops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shadow Ops: Covert Ops in the Sixth World&lt;/strong&gt; is a fan tribute to the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Shadowrun&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; franchise, using a mash-up of Covert Ops and BareBones Fantasy by &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;DwD Studios.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; Inspired by the streamlined mechanics and tactical play of the PC games in particular, it only seemed fitting to mix one of the biggest and best settings in the RPG industry with the fast-playing d00Lite system.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
