<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R.E. Davis on The ChaosGrenade</title>
    <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/author/r.e.-davis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R.E. Davis on The ChaosGrenade</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 13:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://chaosgrenade.com/author/r.e.-davis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>[SIGIL &amp; SHADOW] Factions &amp; Stature</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2022-3-04-faction-stature/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2022-3-04-faction-stature/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Header Art by Luis F. Sanz&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://chaosgrenade.com/page/sigil-and-shadow/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sigil &amp;amp; Shadow&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; strives to cover the tropes of urban fantasy and modern horror &amp;ndash; hunting down monstrous threats, investigating paranormal mysteries, researching hidden magic and communing with powerful entities.  But it also allows players to &lt;em&gt;become&lt;/em&gt; monstrous individuals, treading down paths of power that often put them at odds with both the cities they live in and the others who haunt its streets. While &amp;ldquo;Scooby gang mysteries&amp;rdquo; are a staple of the genre, so to are stories of ancient feuds, dark conspiracies, and rivalries that litter the streets with blood and fire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today we&amp;rsquo;re taking a dive into using &lt;strong&gt;factions&lt;/strong&gt; as part of a Sigil &amp;amp; Shadow campaign.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[SIGIL &amp; SHADOW] Invoking the Fanbase</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2022-2-22-invoking-the-fanbase/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2022-2-22-invoking-the-fanbase/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Header Art by Luis F. Sanz&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First off, apologies for the delay on anything new regarding Sigil &amp;amp; Shadow.&lt;br&gt;
While I&amp;rsquo;ve been distracted trying to get my act together going forward in 2022, some really cool peeps have put together some handy stuff for Sigil &amp;amp; Shadow!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>INTERMIXX - an RPG Mash-Up</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2022-2-19-intermixx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2022-2-19-intermixx/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;INTERMIXX&lt;/strong&gt; is an &lt;em&gt;RPG Mash-Up&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ndash; a remix of cool ideas and styles to create a fun gaming experience all its own. This is a minimalist, DIY rules set. I assume if you&amp;rsquo;re reading this you&amp;rsquo;re already familiar with role-playing games and how they work. I also assume if you find any rules lacking, you know how to steal ideas from other systems or fill in the blanks yourself. So go grab yourself two six-sided dice, something to write on, and some friends. Think up a setting or genre you want to play. Brainstorm, improvise, and most of all: have fun.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mud &amp; Blood: SIGIL &amp; SHADOW Actual Play!</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-11-01-mud-and-blood/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-11-01-mud-and-blood/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was honored to have the chance to run &lt;strong&gt;SIGIL &amp;amp; SHADOW&lt;/strong&gt; for the Mud &amp;amp; Blood podcast&amp;rsquo;s Halloween Special! Just a fun note: this episode essentially counts as Part 5 of &lt;a href=&#34;https://chaosgrenade.com/tags/wythe/&#34;&gt;The Wythe Case&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[SIGIL &amp; SHADOW] Resources</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-10-19-sigil-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-10-19-sigil-resources/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post will be constantly updated with useful documents, play aids and character sheets for &lt;strong&gt;Sigil &amp;amp; Shadow&lt;/strong&gt; as they become available. Check back often, and feel free to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:thechaosgrenade@gmail.com&#34;&gt;email me&lt;/a&gt; any cool homebrewed content you wish to share.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gonzo Mutoids -- Pocket Edition!</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-10-17-gonzo-mutoids-pocket/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-10-17-gonzo-mutoids-pocket/</guid>
      <description>PURCHASE ON ITCH
My love letter to bat-shit crazy, kitchen sink, post apocalyptic settings is now available as a tiny pocket RPG &amp;ndash; this time powered by TRICUBE TALES! All you need is three six-sided dice, some spare tokens and scratch paper.
The base game consists of two tiny booklets (the core game, as well as a bonus GM booklet) that you may print out and fold using the Pocketfold method.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wythe Case, Part 4: A Shattered Nightmare</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-9-26-wythe-case-part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-9-26-wythe-case-part-4/</guid>
      <description>The entity paralyzing Samantha pays no attention to Julia, continuing to attempt to suffocate her with a swarm of shadowy bugs that bleed out from its outstretched hands. Julia hurriedly gestures her spell and screams &amp;ldquo;By my will, I demand you be banished from this place!&amp;rdquo; In a flash, ghostly arms wisp out and grab the horror, dragging it into the mirror as it howls in anguish. Julia rushes to Samantha&amp;rsquo;s side as she finally wakes up, sitting straight up and screaming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wythe Case, Part 3: Dead End Friends</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-9-26-wythe-case-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-9-26-wythe-case-part-3/</guid>
      <description>Samantha couldn&amp;rsquo;t sleep the nights following her encounter at the Wythe Estate. Any time she closed her eyes, that wretched man-bug with the hollowed eyes was there&amp;hellip; its severed and inhuman teeth. When she was awake, especially on the nights following, something else was there.
It hid in plain sight &amp;ndash; even when she meditated and gazed across the curtain into the Echo, it was only there the edges of the periphery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wythe Case, Part 2: Fight or Flight</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-9-21-wythe-case-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-9-21-wythe-case-part-2/</guid>
      <description>This narrative is a continuing example of gameplay for Sigil &amp;amp; Shadow, my role-playing game of Urban Fantasy &amp;amp; Occult Horror. We left Samantha Cane being pursued by some kind of gnarly half-humanoid, half-insect monstrosity chasing her out of an abandoned estate.
 You can catch up on part one here You can also check out Samantha Cane&amp;rsquo;s Character Sheet Learn more about Sigil &amp;amp; Shadow here   Our Story Continues Samantha runs out into dark night, sliding in the mud and frantically trying to find an escape from the Wythe estate grounds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wythe Case, Part 1: Break In</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-9-17-wythe-case-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-9-17-wythe-case-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Samantha Cane exits her ride, tips the driver, and proceeds to walk down the wet street towards the Wythe estate. Myrtle and Benjamin Wythe, as the local stories tell, were a couple found mutilated and murdered in their upper-end mansion back in the 1980s. They were pillars of the community — he was a business owner and once city council member; she was active in the PTA and their church. Both were found in their living room, tongues cut out and their hearts removed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now on Neocities</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-9-9-now-on-neocities/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-9-9-now-on-neocities/</guid>
      <description>The ChaosGrenade is now being hosted on Neocities.Org. If that name raises some slight nostalgia, it&amp;rsquo;s no coincidence, as it&amp;rsquo;s a nod to the old days of Geocities &amp;ndash; back before social media when everyone had a website, and we &amp;ldquo;networked&amp;rdquo; through web rings. I figured it was time to quit piggy-backing off my brother&amp;rsquo;s webhost, and Neocities met all my needs.
What does this mean for the site, exactly? Only that I&amp;rsquo;ve chosen to remain as a &amp;ldquo;static&amp;rdquo; web blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Sigil &amp; Shadow] Julia Grave, Shadowed Occultist</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-9-5-julia-grave/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-9-5-julia-grave/</guid>
      <description>This is Part 2 of a series showing game play examples for Sigil &amp;amp; Shadow. You can read Part 1 here.
Today we&amp;rsquo;re having a look at a sample Shadowed character. These are the monstrous characters of our game, having embraced a darker side of them in exchange for paranormal power. Instead of defining how every vampire, werewolf, zombie or other thing that goes bump in the night works, we&amp;rsquo;ve established four broad courts of shadow &amp;ndash; the Ravenous, the Devoted, the Afflicted and the Hosts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Sigil &amp; Shadow] Seeking Samantha Cane</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-8-22-seeking-samantha-cane/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 08:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-8-22-seeking-samantha-cane/</guid>
      <description>This is the first part in a series of blogs that with the hopes of being walkthrough examples for Sigil &amp;amp; Shadow. Future posts will show sample gameplay concepts, but for today we&amp;rsquo;ll start out with some character creation. Let&amp;rsquo;s meet Samantha Cane, a woman in her late twenties who is obsessed with the supernatural.
If you haven&amp;rsquo;t picked up a copy yet, I recommend first checking out my previews at the Osprey Games Blog so some of these terms make sense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Released: SIGIL &amp; SHADOW</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-7-22-sigil-and-shadow-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 08:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-7-22-sigil-and-shadow-release/</guid>
      <description>The invocation is complete – the key to my nightmares, made manifest and in my hands. Sigil &amp;amp; Shadow has been years in the works. So many gaming sessions. Years of feedback. Lots of caffeine, bad food decisions, late night drives, music play lists, awkward hours spent trying not to wake up my child, two fucking presidential elections and surviving a pandemic have gone into making this. Finally, it’s a finished dream; a physical artifact that I can touch and pass off to you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pulling Back the Curtain (on Sigil &amp; Shadow)</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-2-16-pulling-back-the-curtain/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 12:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-2-16-pulling-back-the-curtain/</guid>
      <description>Out Now!
Ghosts. Vampires. The monster in your closet. The bogeyman under your bed. The cryptid you read about online. They’re all real. They lurk in our shadows. They linger in our reflections. Good people make pacts with demons they find online. Creatures from beyond time prowl the city streets. Forgotten rituals are reborn as viral memes. The rich and powerful consort with ancient beings behind boardroom doors. Entities beyond our comprehension exploit our desires, gorge themselves on our fears, and manifest as our nightmares.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Little Heroes, Big Adventures</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-2-14-little-heroes-big-adventures/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 12:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-2-14-little-heroes-big-adventures/</guid>
      <description>This may come as a surprise, but while many know me for being into grim settings (cyberpunk, dystopian, horror etc) one of my favorite types of fantasy is where tiny heroes go on big journeys underfoot of humanity. SHROOM GOONS was my love letter to the genre. But for today, I want to shine a spot light on other indie titles that have cemented a place of warm, child-like wonder in my otherwise cold beating heart:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Death and Return of The ChaosGrenade</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2020-10-12-death-and-return/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 10:39:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2020-10-12-death-and-return/</guid>
      <description>The old blog site is dead. May this one endure.
Last week I was made aware that adware had infiltrated my site. Certain pages and methods of access (like Google) resulted in redirects to spam and phishing sites.
I have no ill feelings towards Wordpress, except as someone who infrequently blogs it was becoming a chore to keep up to date. Several times in the past I&amp;rsquo;ve had issues with plug-ins, themes, and even the software updates themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rambling On: NEUROCITY</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2020-08-13-rambling-on-neurocity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 20:46:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2020-08-13-rambling-on-neurocity/</guid>
      <description>Gavriel Quiroga was really cool to send me a review copy of his game Neurocity,a dystopian nightmare RPG that has recently released following a successful Kickstarter. It’s clocking in at 126 pages for the PDF, although that includes covers, a couple pages of backer names, and a few blanks that I believe are just there for layout purposes.
NEUROCITY was pitched to me as PARANOIA meets Clive Barker, and I feel that is accurate and an understatement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[UPDATE] SIGIL &amp; SHADOW</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2020-06-17-update-sigil-shadow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 15:46:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2020-06-17-update-sigil-shadow/</guid>
      <description>Looks like Amazon UK has let the cat out of the bag:
SIGIL &amp;amp; SHADOW: A Roleplaying Game of Urban Fantasy and Occult Horror is due out next year from Osprey Games. I’ve been really excited to be among the next wave of their RPG releases — you can expect some upcoming rambles about Romance of the Perilous Land and Paleomythic.
For now, though, I felt an up-to-date post about where S&amp;amp;S is in 2020 is important; especially since the Amazon listing has resulted in lots of traffic at older posts from 2014-2015.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NEON CITY OVERDRIVE</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2020-05-12-neon-city-overdrive/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 15:47:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2020-05-12-neon-city-overdrive/</guid>
      <description>Cut To The Chase Neon City Overdrive is a new cyberpunk rpg put out by Nathan Russell/Peril Planet (creator of Freeform Unlimited), and is available in PDF for $8. From the sales pitch from their DTRPG Listing:
NEON CITY OVERDRIVE is a fast-playing RPG of cyberpunk action. With a focus on story and action, character creation is fast and the rules are intuitive. Create any kind of cyberpunk character you want and throw them into the action within minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RAMBLING ON: TRICUBE TALES</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2020-01-27-rambling-on-tricube-tales/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 19:35:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2020-01-27-rambling-on-tricube-tales/</guid>
      <description>I need to talk about this game, Tricube Tales by Richard Woolcock of Zadmar&amp;rsquo;s Games. There’s a lot I want to say about it, which is crazy because it’s also pretty lite and simple. Also, the damn game is free (full thing in the preview) so you can easily check it for yourself. Yeah, it’s 49 pages, but it’s using that fancy Phone PDF format so it’s really a quick read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MAIN SEQUENCE: TRI-FOLD EDITION</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-12-09-main-sequence-tri-fold-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 18:18:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-12-09-main-sequence-tri-fold-edition/</guid>
      <description>What is MAIN SEQUENCE? MAIN SEQUENCE is a fast, “Rules-Necessary” science fiction RPG written by Matt Bryant.
It uses the WyRM System, originally found in titles like Warrior, Rogue &amp;amp; Mage and Resolute, Adventurer &amp;amp; Genius.
MAIN SEQUENCE characters have three Attributes (Soldier, Agent and Tech). They choose a handful of skills and Tags, some equipment, and then they’re off on their planetary adventures! Folks who are wanting a traditional space RPG with a little meat on the bone, but don’t want to be bogged down with bloated catalogs of tech or complex space battles will be at home in MAIN SEQUENCE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SHROOM GOONS Update!</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-09-26-shroom-goons-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 15:50:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-09-26-shroom-goons-update/</guid>
      <description>Some big news regarding SHROOM GOONS!
First off, we got third place in the Goon Jam on Itch.io! Thanks to everyone who’s supported this little title and left amazing feedback and reviews. And to the person who left a 1 star without comment — why do you hate fun?
Second off, there is now an updated SHROOM GOONS available on Itch! Minor edits, small clarifications, expanded Difficulty Scores, and a Referee section that offers some ways to tweak and handle difficult encounters &amp;amp; challenges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SHROOM GOONS — A New Free Title!</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-08-20-shroom-goons-a-new-free-title/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 15:08:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-08-20-shroom-goons-a-new-free-title/</guid>
      <description>SHROOM GOONS is a “Spore-Core” Fantasy Trip for Weird People. A hack of Nate Treme’s Tunnel Goons , players take on the role of tiny mushroom folk on a big adventure! Inspired by Fragglerock, Smurfs, The Littles, Toy Story and other childhood “tiny people” stories. It’s weird, it’s fun, it’s easy to pick up and play. And it features artwork by Skullfungus!
 Arm yourself with a sewing needle sword, a button shield, and ready your matchstick torch!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FABRICATED VENTURERS — a Classless Hack for Vieja Escuela</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-07-25-fabricated-venturers-a-classless-hack-for-vieja-escuela/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 19:33:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-07-25-fabricated-venturers-a-classless-hack-for-vieja-escuela/</guid>
      <description>I have written a classless, patchwork/piecemeal character hack for Vieja Escuela. Taking advantage of the format of VE: Pamphlet Edition, it’s written as a modular variant to the Character Creation rules. Just swap out and use without changing the rest of the game! Or you can just print out, fold up, and tuck it in your original VE rulebook.
The Concept Fabricated Venturers ditches classes. Everyone starts as a d6 hit die character, proficient in simple weapons and Leather armor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VIEJA ESCUELA: Pamphlet Edition</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-06-28-vieja-escuela-pamphlet-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 21:07:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-06-28-vieja-escuela-pamphlet-edition/</guid>
      <description>I have taken the core rules of Vieja Escuela (which I’ve praised on herebefore) and repackaged it. As the name implies, this version is intended to be printed out and folded into three “zig-zag” or “accordion” style pamphlets (Character Creation, Game Rules, &amp;amp; Tables). Of course, it also looks good on tablets, or printed out and left on their own. Do whatever pleases you! This was a first time project for me using Affinity Publisher, and I’m pretty happy to share the results!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWESOME D.P.S. — A Free, Narrative-Driven Dice Pool System</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-05-28-awesome-d-p-s-a-free-narrative-driven-dice-pool-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 14:35:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-05-28-awesome-d-p-s-a-free-narrative-driven-dice-pool-system/</guid>
      <description>AWESOME D.P.S. (Dice Pool System) is a fast playing, narrative-driven dice pool RPG framework that is now live on itch.io! as a Pay-What-You-Want Pamphlet RPG.
The goal was to create a game that captures the best part of a dice pool system (grabbing handfuls of dice and feeling like a bad-ass) while minimizing stat blocks and keeping the math simple. Inspired and built off Diogo Nogueira’s Lost in the Fantasy World, these rules were written for gaming sessions that focus more on story and narrative flow than stat crunching or tactical play.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting Anarchy</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-05-13-fanstuff-revisiting-anarchy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 21:15:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-05-13-fanstuff-revisiting-anarchy/</guid>
      <description>Shadowrun: Anarchy is a title that I often call a “flawed gem” — a great game marred by poor execution. Rushed edits, a somewhat schizophrenic design (is it a core rulebook? Is it a supplement?), stretching itself thin trying to please both traditional SR veterans and newcomer storygamers. But despite all of that, underneath the rubble you can find the chassis of a slick, streamlined and adaptable dicepool system.
While I’m excited to see where the Sixth World Edition is heading, I find myself slinking back into my copy of Anarchy (goblinized warts and all).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>D·10 TOOLKIT: RULING DIFFICULTY</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-05-09-d10-toolkit-ruling-difficulty/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 14:23:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-05-09-d10-toolkit-ruling-difficulty/</guid>
      <description>For today’s article in the D·10 Toolkit series, I wanted to take a look at the core mechanics and, specifically, how difficulty and challenges are expressed in the die rolls, and how you can change it up for your own games.
Drive·10 was designed for fast rulings and game play, and with it I used a very straight-forward approach to determining the difficulty of the roll.
 All rolls are 1d10 + Proficiency (total bonuses), succeed on a total of 10+.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pamphlets, Zines, and Other Fun Things</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-05-02-pamphlets-zines-and-other-fun-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 15:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-05-02-pamphlets-zines-and-other-fun-things/</guid>
      <description>Another spotlight post of cool indie/DIY RPG stuff and other fun things from around the geek webs.
The RPG Pamphlet Craze! Nate Treme (Highland Paranormal Society/ In The Light of a Ghost Star) has made some awesome pamphlet dungeons, and hosted an Pamphlet Dungeon Jam that has resulted in some incredible creations!
I had received hard copies of his Temple of the Bat Serpent and The Mephitic Laboratory of the Pescamancerand was impressed with how much you could put on a standard tri-fold adventure module!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ATHAS: DARK SUN, DESERT PLANET (SB&amp;CS)</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-04-29-athas-dark-sun-desert-planet-sbcs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 15:15:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-04-29-athas-dark-sun-desert-planet-sbcs/</guid>
      <description>Filed Under: Campaign Ideas I Need Out of My Head.
Premise: The Dark Sun setting re-imagined for the space fantasy game Solar Blades &amp;amp; Cosmic Spells.
Other Influences: Dune, Heavy Metal, and the artwork of Moebius.
Preface: I really love Dark Sun on the surface. The core AD&amp;amp;D 2e boxset did a great job setting up the world of Athas and showing the “world at a glance” so to speak. The places where I start to tune out is when it essentially shoe-horns D&amp;amp;Disms into its unique setting, and the metaplot of events didn’t really impress me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>D·10 TOOLKIT: EXPANDING ON TAGS</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-04-25-d10-toolkit-expanding-on-tags/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 16:34:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-04-25-d10-toolkit-expanding-on-tags/</guid>
      <description>Tags in Drive·10 make up all the cool traits, powers, skills and features a character can have. When I set out to design the framework, I decided that instead of trying to make a large, encompassing list like we’ve done with other games, to instead create a simple guide to how Tags operate at the meta level. I took inspiration from systems like Fate and Savage Worlds in that I wanted someone to easily skin and translate whatever it is they’re wanting for their character into a game mechanic in a moment’s notice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>D·10 TOOLKIT: ATTRIBUTES &amp; VOCATIONS</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-04-18-d10-toolkit-attributes-vocations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 14:22:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-04-18-d10-toolkit-attributes-vocations/</guid>
      <description>The Drive·10 Framework was written to be as fast, compact, and complete as possible. I wanted the core to be as essential as can be, so that it would be easy to take and replace rules as needed. Today I’m starting* a new series of blog posts, musing on different ways you can expand or hack the Drive·10 system to accommodate different needs in a role-playing game. Along the way I also hope the shed some light on why I went with certain design choices over others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DRIVE·10 MOCKUPS: GONZO MUTOIDS</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-04-11-drive10-mockups-gonzo-mutoids/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 15:02:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-04-11-drive10-mockups-gonzo-mutoids/</guid>
      <description>Much like the Dungeon Delvers mock up, this post provides a few GONZO MUTOID WASTELAND CRUST PUNKS characters that you can either use as pre-gens, NPCs, or just inspiration for building your own.
Radjak, a Shifty Telepathic Bug Scoundrel. Radjak is a typical rogue you’d find gambling in any post-Frag trade hub. He likes using his telepathy during games of Globwox Hold ‘Em. His strategy isn’t just to sense who may have the better hand, but to pick up on other cheaters so he can try to call their shenanigans out before anyone suspects him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GONZO MUTOID WASTELAND CRUST PUNKS HAS RETURNED!</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-04-08-gonzo-mutoid-wasteland-crust-punks-has-returned/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 15:30:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-04-08-gonzo-mutoid-wasteland-crust-punks-has-returned/</guid>
      <description>The crazy, zany, bat-shit insane post-apocalyptic project that triggered the creation of Drive·10 has now finally glued itself back together! GONZO MUTOID WASTELAND CRUST PUNKS is now available to everyone who pays $2+ to support D·10 on Itch. Inspired by RIFTS, Gamma World, TMNT, Rick &amp;amp; Morty, Adventure Time, Heavy Metal, Super Jail and all sorts of other junk I like, GMWCP is an attempt at a rules-lite game of a fractured reality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DRIVE·10: Now On Itch!</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-03-25-drive10-now-on-itch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 14:49:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-03-25-drive10-now-on-itch/</guid>
      <description>Drive·10, our latest RPG Framework, has been released on Itch.io!
This is an updated and revised version of the original game released last year. There have been a number of tweaks, adjustments, an addition or two, and some necessary editorial passes.
**Drive·10 **is a fast, simple, traditional tabletop role-playing system with easy character creation and streamlined mechanics. Designed for quick pick up and play — brainstorm a setting, make characters, and get to playing all in one evening.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rambling On: Solar Blades &amp; Cosmic Spells</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-03-05-rambling-on-solar-blades-cosmic-spells/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 16:05:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-03-05-rambling-on-solar-blades-cosmic-spells/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been a hell of a wait, but at long last I have Diogo Nogueira’s latest offering: &lt;strong&gt;Solar Blades &amp;amp; Cosmic Spells.&lt;/strong&gt; Built off the same rules as his sword &amp;amp; sorcery offering &lt;em&gt;(Sharp Swords &amp;amp; Sinister Spells),&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;SB&amp;amp;CS&lt;/strong&gt; is more than a science-fantasy re-skin — it is a &lt;em&gt;massive&lt;/em&gt; offering of everything you would want or need for a gonzo, pulpy space adventure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rambling on: In The Light of a Ghost Star</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-01-29-rambling-on-in-the-light-of-a-ghost-star/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 16:59:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-01-29-rambling-on-in-the-light-of-a-ghost-star/</guid>
      <description>Short, sweet, and to the point: **In The Light of a Ghost Star **by Nate Treme of Highland Paranormal Society is a wonderful zine-rpg that is easy to pick up and run after a quick read through. Players take on the role of martian explorers being dropped off on a dead Earth to explore its treacherous ruins filled with strange inhabitants. That’s literally all the story we have, and it’s all that’s really needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rambling on: Vieja Escuela</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-01-20-rambling-on-vieja-escuela/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 18:08:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-01-20-rambling-on-vieja-escuela/</guid>
      <description>I’m mad at myself for not blogging about this until now. In the past year or so we’ve seen a lot of cool minimalist and “OSR-Adjacent” D&amp;amp;D clones come out. Black Hack 2e, Untold Adventures, and Knave are a few of the ones I enjoy. But the one that stole the show is a little booklet named Vieja Escuela, a Spanish RPG that had been translated to several languages (including English).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5-Point Conflict Map</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2018-12-07-5-point-conflict-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 20:15:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2018-12-07-5-point-conflict-map/</guid>
      <description>This isn’t anything original — just a cool idea I had for a tool to map factional conflicts in an RPG. Specifically it came to mind thinking about urban fantasy settings (whether that’s modern or large cities in fantastic campaigns, like Sharn in Eberron.) I feel like the best opportunities for adventure and role-playing occur whenever multiple factions with no clear alliances struggle among themselves.
I wanted a way to quickly map out who’s with who, and whom are they fighting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ironsworn &#43; Solo Gaming!</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2018-11-08-ironsworn-solo-gaming/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 18:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2018-11-08-ironsworn-solo-gaming/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://anchor.fm/thechaosgrenade/episodes/Ironsworn--Solo-Gaming-e2h4g3&#34;&gt;LISTEN TO EPISODE 4!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This episode of the podcast, we’re discussing solo role-playing and my impressions on &lt;strong&gt;Ironsworn!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://anchor.fm/thechaosgrenade/embed/episodes/Ironsworn--Solo-Gaming-e2h4g3/a-a5ua86&#34; width=&#34;500px&#34; height=&#34;100px&#34; frameborder=&#34;1&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Raven’s Scroll: An Ironsworn Game Log</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2018-11-08-the-ravens-scroll-an-ironsworn-game-log/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 17:50:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2018-11-08-the-ravens-scroll-an-ironsworn-game-log/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a play log / session report of my first “solo-rpg” experience using &lt;strong&gt;Ironsworn&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.  &lt;em&gt;My full review of the game &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;can be read here!&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: IRONSWORN</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2018-11-07-review-ironsworn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 15:39:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2018-11-07-review-ironsworn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“In the Ironsworn tabletop roleplaying game, you are a hero sworn to undertake perilous quests in the dark fantasy setting of the Ironlands. You will explore untracked wilds, fight desperate battles, forge bonds with isolated communities, and reveal the secrets of this harsh land. Most importantly, you will swear iron vows and see them fulfilled—no matter the cost.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call-Ins, Play by Post, and Size Matters!</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2018-11-01-call-ins-play-by-post-and-size-matters/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 19:42:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2018-11-01-call-ins-play-by-post-and-size-matters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://anchor.fm/thechaosgrenade/episodes/Call-Ins--Play-by-Post--and-Size-Matters-e2g17r&#34;&gt;Listen to Episode 3!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We kick things off with some Call-Ins! Then I welcome Matt Bryant on board to ramble with me about Play-by-Post gaming, and when gaming groups get too big.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://anchor.fm/thechaosgrenade/embed/episodes/Call-Ins--Play-by-Post--and-Size-Matters-e2g17r/a-a671jb&#34; width=&#34;500px&#34; height=&#34;100px&#34; frameborder=&#34;1&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hearts &amp; Souls (and DriveThru METAL)</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2018-10-26-hearts-souls-and-drivethru-metal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 21:10:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2018-10-26-hearts-souls-and-drivethru-metal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://anchor.fm/thechaosgrenade/episodes/Hearts--Souls-and-DriveThru-METAL-e2fubv&#34;&gt;Our second episode of &lt;strong&gt;The ChaosGrenade Podcast!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today’s topics include: the Hearts &amp;amp; Souls 2e Kickstarter, and DTRPG’s new top tiers (and what games shockingly are in them!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://anchor.fm/thechaosgrenade/embed/episodes/Hearts--Souls-and-DriveThru-METAL-e2fubv/a-a63cdi&#34; width=&#34;500px&#34; height=&#34;100px&#34; frameborder=&#34;1&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ChaosGrenade Podcast!</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2018-10-24-the-chaosgrenade-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 21:17:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2018-10-24-the-chaosgrenade-podcast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://anchor.fm/thechaosgrenade/episodes/Obligatory-Intro-Episode-e2e6e8&#34;&gt;1st Episode of &lt;strong&gt;The ChaosGrenade Podcast!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our very first episode, I talk about our tastes in tabletop RPGs, the OSR as an idea farm, and I attempt to make Rolpunk a thing again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://anchor.fm/thechaosgrenade/embed/episodes/Obligatory-Intro-Episode-e2e6e8/a-a5ua86&#34; width=&#34;500px&#34; height=&#34;100px&#34; frameborder=&#34;1&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drive·10 Mockups: Dungeon Delvers</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2018-08-06-drive10-mockups-dungeon-delvers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 13:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2018-08-06-drive10-mockups-dungeon-delvers/</guid>
      <description>Note: This post is now updated to the current 1.1 Revision of Drive·10
Today I wanted to show some mock-ups for using the D·10 framework to run a high-action, mid-fantasy dungeon delving game. Let’s start with a few player characters, and then I’ll also share some sample NPCs.
Player Characters Garn, a Nomadic Barbarian Garn is the combat power house of this trio. The GM has approved that his vocation of _Nomadic Barbarian _not only grants proficiency in combat, but also establishes a background in wilderness survival.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drive·10 is Out Now!</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2018-07-30-drive10-is-out-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 16:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2018-07-30-drive10-is-out-now/</guid>
      <description>**Drive·10 **is the latest framework from ChaosGrenade. A fast, simple d10 system with a quick approach to character creation. Designed for quick pick up and play — brainstorm a setting, make characters, and get to playing all in one evening. Ideal for one-shots, short campaigns, convention play and more.
 Simple d10 mechanic inspired by CarPG — roll the die, add your proficiency, score 10+ to succeed. Easy as that. **Streamlined Tag **mechanic gives you an easy approach to defining features of your character.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keep an Eye On: Against the Darkmaster</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2018-07-23-keep-an-eye-on-against-the-darkmaster/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 11:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2018-07-23-keep-an-eye-on-against-the-darkmaster/</guid>
      <description>I am shocked that I’m not seeing any buzz over this awesome upcoming title. Let’s remedy that.
Against the Darkmaster is a game that started out as a clone/house-ruled version of Middle Earth Role-Playing and Rolemaster but has evolved into its own game. The authors list various inspirations from books by Tolkien, Brooks and Goodkind to movies from 70’s and 80’s like Dragonslayer and Krull. They even have an extensive Spotify playlist of heavy metal music and really you should just go look at their God-damned awesome looking website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Plant Hack: Mutant Plants for The Rad Hack</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2017-05-11-the-plant-hack-mutant-plants-for-the-rad-hack/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2017 18:41:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2017-05-11-the-plant-hack-mutant-plants-for-the-rad-hack/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Mutant class in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.drivethrurpg.com/product/187874/The-RadHack&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Rad Hack&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is pretty flexible — you can easily be a mutant animal, plant, or some other strange humanoid. Still, I’ve had friends, followers, and even my spouse talk about how they wished the “Mutant Plant” was a class on its own. I decided to homebrew my own variant Plant class by re-skinning powers that already existed in the game. Enjoy!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GUTTERPUNK SESSION 2: “Come to Zom Zom’s — a Place to Eat!”</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2017-04-23-gutterpunk-session-2-come-to-zom-zoms-a-place-to-eat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2017 18:28:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2017-04-23-gutterpunk-session-2-come-to-zom-zoms-a-place-to-eat/</guid>
      <description>_This is a play report for **Gutterpunk Sprawl-Crawl, **a play-by-post campaign using **The Rad Hack. **This setting entails violence, drug use, and depraved morals — consider this your NSFW warning. _
When we left off last session, Leper Prawn and Absolvo had made it out alive from the radioactive sewers and have emerged about a block away from **Zom Zom’s, **a notorious restaurant that is a hub for all sorts of mutants, nomads, and biker gangs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gutterpunk Session 1: Down In It</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2017-04-05-gutterpunk-session-1-down-in-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 23:23:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2017-04-05-gutterpunk-session-1-down-in-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is the first play report of **&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Gutterpunk Sprawl Crawl&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;, **a gonzo urban setting using &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;The Rad Hack&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;. Crude language ahead — consider this your NSFW warning.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gutterpunk Sprawl Crawl: Setting Stuff</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2017-03-29-gutterpunk-sprawl-crawl-setting-stuff/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 22:19:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2017-03-29-gutterpunk-sprawl-crawl-setting-stuff/</guid>
      <description>Warning: Harsh NSFW Language Ahead
I recently began work on an obscene sandbox that primarily uses **The Rad Hack **but also borrows from other titles like Cyber Hacked, Augmented Reality, Other Dust and any thematically appropriate stuff I find in the OSR community.
I’ve actually begun running it as a Play-by-Post via a private Facebook Group. This format actually works well because it means I can troll Google Images for inspirational artwork to every scene and character, and we also keep an “Out of Character” chat open in messenger for “table talk” moments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Witch of the Citrine Tower</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2017-02-09-the-witch-of-the-citrine-tower/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 22:31:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2017-02-09-the-witch-of-the-citrine-tower/</guid>
      <description>_This post is some raw ideas transcribed from some very loose notes from a one-shot adventure I put together for **Swords &amp;amp; Wizardry. **__I present them here as a loose framework for anyone to use however they wish in their own games. _
The immediate area surrounding the town of Silverbrooke has long been protected by the “witch” of the Citrine Tower. Though human, she’s been around as long as a lot of elves can remember.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on High Valor</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2016-11-18-reflections-on-high-valor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 18:29:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2016-11-18-reflections-on-high-valor/</guid>
      <description>Six years ago, I had my view on gaming flipped on its head. I was at the end of a two-year 4e D&amp;amp;D campaign; one that saw decks of power cards, miniatures, three different desktop applications, and combat encounters that lasted entire evenings. It was clear that, while we had a blast, that the days of such bloated systems were in need of ending. We needed something lighter, more elegant, and easier to run in the fewer hours we had.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ramblings on Shadowrun: Anarchy</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2016-10-17-ramblings-on-shadowrun-anarchy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 13:57:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2016-10-17-ramblings-on-shadowrun-anarchy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, it happened.&lt;br&gt;
Catalyst Game Labs released &lt;em&gt;**&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.drivethrurpg.com/product/194759/Shadowrun-Anarchy?hot60=0&amp;amp;src=hnum&#34;&gt;Shadowrun: Anarchy,&lt;/a&gt; **&lt;/em&gt; an “alternate rules set” that aims at letting players run the shadows of the Sixth World in a more story-driven rules set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking for a solid, full review of &lt;em&gt;Anarchy&lt;/em&gt; I highly recommend the &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Casting Shadows review.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;  Otherwise, I’m just going to sit here and gush fanboy for a moment…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rota Fortunae: A Simple Fantasy RPG Framework</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2016-04-18-rota-fortunae-a-simple-fantasy-rpg-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2016 04:49:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2016-04-18-rota-fortunae-a-simple-fantasy-rpg-framework/</guid>
      <description>Rota Fortunae is a simple fantasy rpg framework driven by CarPG.
We took the base rules and repackaged it as a complete, stand alone 16-page PDF fantasy game. In addition to showcasing the system in a clean layout, we added all sorts of fun stuff:
 Expanded Skills &amp;amp; Tags A simple magic system with expanded options. 8 fantasy races (plus humans) Additional house-rule options to expand or simplify the game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacking WR&amp;M to Fate’s Wheel</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2016-04-03-hacking-wrm-to-fates-wheel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 01:17:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2016-04-03-hacking-wrm-to-fates-wheel/</guid>
      <description>Today’s post isn’t so much an add-on to **CarPG **as it is a brainstorm on a system hack for _Warrior, Rogue &amp;amp; Mage— _converting it to the d10 or Fate’s Wheel mechanic that CarPG uses.
The ease of cross-pollination between the two is not a coincidence since most of the games we crank out here at The ChaosGrenade are either based on the WyRM System or grew from it. The goal of this blog post is to present a variant resolution mechanic for WR&amp;amp;M while allowing the character creation process to remain intact with minimal edits or conversions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using CarPG for Play-By-Post</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2016-03-19-using-carpg-for-play-by-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2016 22:15:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2016-03-19-using-carpg-for-play-by-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First off, if you haven’t seen it yet: **&lt;a href=&#34;http://chaosgrenade.com/games/carpg/&#34;&gt;CarPG&lt;/a&gt; **is a new diceless rules-lite RPG framework written by my buddy Matt Bryant (the guy behind _Main Sequence.) _&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While he designed it  as a game to play on road trips with your buds, I’ve found it _incredibly _useful as a mechanic for playing Play By Post rpgs. In my past experience, play-by-posts worked either one of three ways: 1) The dice rolls were either handled completely by the moderator, leaving a sense of control out for the players. 2) The entire game was purely narrative focused, which while fun often felt more like a writing exercise than a game. And then lastly, 3) The die rolls were handled like normal (either on the honor system  or with online dice rollers), and as a result the game system itself really bogged down the pace of the game.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[WHITE STAR]: 5 Quick &amp; Dirty Supplement Reviews</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2015-06-15-white-star-5-quick-dirty-supplement-reviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 01:41:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2015-06-15-white-star-5-quick-dirty-supplement-reviews/</guid>
      <description>Today’s post is looking at five different supplements available from RPGNow, each of them no more than a few bucks. I’ve been enjoying the hell out of **White Star. **And one of the solid strengths of it is the amazing community and third-party support that is running with it.
Psionics **Author: **Matthew Skail
**Cost: **$1.99
**Page Count: **11 (including cover and license)
_Psionics _is what it says on the tin: a psionicist class for White Star.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WHITE STAR: A Rambling Review</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2015-05-29-white-star-a-rambling-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2015 05:38:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2015-05-29-white-star-a-rambling-review/</guid>
      <description>I have a curse where every time I say “I don’t need another OSR game!” I open up my wallet and acquire another one.
**White Star **is written by James M. Spahn and released by Barrel Rider Games. The gist of it is they took the rules from Swords &amp;amp; Wizardry Whitebox and hacked it into their own super slick science fiction game. Now, I’m already a rabid fan of Kevin Crawford’s _Stars Without Number, _and I was hesitant to toss $10 at a lighter, simpler game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SHADOW OPS: Street Samurai</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2015-05-07-shadow-ops-street-samurai/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2015 15:39:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2015-05-07-shadow-ops-street-samurai/</guid>
      <description>Oh man, the Street Samurai.
Years before I would know who Molly Millions was, I was a dorky 9 year old kid who laughed when my dad referred to my older brother’s weekend pastime as “Dungeons &amp;amp; Dumbass.” But then one Saturday morning, my brother had left out a book he borrowed from a friend. A book with a hot elf chick on the cover in cut off jeans, a book filled with gritty sci-fi urban landscapes, tribal shamans, and fantasy characters with electrodes plugged into their skull.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SHADOW OPS: Elven Adept</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2015-05-06-shadow-ops-elven-adept/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 20:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2015-05-06-shadow-ops-elven-adept/</guid>
      <description>So, after playing **Shadowrun Chronicles: Boston Lockdown **a bunch this week with Tim Kirk (of Silverlion Studios), I was inspired to whip-up **SHADOW OPS: Covert Ops in the Sixth World. **It’s a fan tribute to the Shadowrun franchise, inspired by the gameplay of the recent PC games using a mash-up of COVERT OPS and BareBones Fantasy from DwD Studios. I’m pretty happy with what I threw together between studying for finals, and the initial reactions from the BBF Community on G+ have been stellar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SHADOW OPS</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2015-05-06-shadow-ops/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2015 21:16:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2015-05-06-shadow-ops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shadow Ops: Covert Ops in the Sixth World&lt;/strong&gt; is a fan tribute to the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Shadowrun&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; franchise, using a mash-up of Covert Ops and BareBones Fantasy by &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;DwD Studios.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; Inspired by the streamlined mechanics and tactical play of the PC games in particular, it only seemed fitting to mix one of the biggest and best settings in the RPG industry with the fast-playing d00Lite system.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mashed-Up: The Strange, Accelerated.</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2015-04-13-mashed-up-the-strange-accelerated/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2015 13:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2015-04-13-mashed-up-the-strange-accelerated/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What follows is a set of house rules I originally came up with to run&lt;a href=&#34;http://thestrangerpg.com/&#34;&gt;The Strange&lt;/a&gt; by Monte Cook Games using &lt;strong&gt;Fate Accelerated&lt;/strong&gt; by Evil Hat Studios. At the time, I wasn’t too sure how I felt about the Cypher System. Since then, I’ve ran quite a few games using both The Strange and the &lt;strong&gt;Cypher System Rulebook.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s grown on me, and it’s one of my favorite new systems.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Warrior, Rogue &amp; Mage: Now CC-BY &#43; SRD</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2015-01-28-warrior-rogue-mage-now-cc-by-srd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2015 17:44:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2015-01-28-warrior-rogue-mage-now-cc-by-srd/</guid>
      <description>We here at ChaosGrenade Press want to boost the signal of some really amazing news!

Michael Wolf (aka Stargazer) recently gave a big gift to the gaming community:
Warrior, Rogue &amp;amp; Mage now has a System Reference Documentand that document is released under the Creative Commons Unported license! In human words, there is now a simple core document of the WyRM system that is completely open for reuse in gaming projects (even commercial ones) as long as proper credit is given (which is more than fair!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Campsite Ambush: A BareBones Fantasy Sample Combat</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2014-02-27-campsite-ambush-a-barebones-fantasy-sample-combat/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2014 01:18:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2014-02-27-campsite-ambush-a-barebones-fantasy-sample-combat/</guid>
      <description>Combat using the BareBones Fantasy Rules can be a bit tricky: overall, it’s a pretty simple system to pick up and run. But it’s deceptive in its simplicity and flexibility — folks who are used to more detailed systems, like D&amp;amp;D, get thrown off by some of the streamlined rules calls. Others probably mistake the BareBones d00Lite system for being, well, lite. I enjoy this system because it falls under what I categorize more as “rules necessary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVERT OPS is OUT NOW!</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2013-12-13-covert-ops-is-out-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2013 22:14:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2013-12-13-covert-ops-is-out-now/</guid>
      <description>**COVERT OPS **by **DWD STUDIOS **has launched ahead of schedule! 
COVERT OPS is a modern day role-playing game of paramlitary action and espionage, using the d00Lite System (that same found in BareBones Fantasy.) At the risk of repeating myself any further, I’d like to point any new readers to my previews BBF Review and CO Preview:
COVERT OPS Sneak Peek BareBones Fantasy Review All of the excitement I had previously remains.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sneak Peek: COVERT OPS from DwD Studios</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2013-10-29-sneak-peak-covert-ops-from-dwd-studios/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2013 18:11:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2013-10-29-sneak-peak-covert-ops-from-dwd-studios/</guid>
      <description>Today’s post falls on the anniversary of the BareBones Fantasy release. For those who missed out, BBF was a solid percentile based role-playing game that captured the joys and feels of traditional dungeon crawlers and fantasy games, but with very quick-playing rules and fast-paced charts that allowed you to stock your campaign world in a jiffy. (Feel free to recap with my full review.)
After a very successful launch, BBF continued to be supported with a line of equal quality products that included a brush stroked campaign setting, a book of optional races, a few adventures and even a free e-zine with content provided from the community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compelled by Fate (Accelerated)</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2013-09-07-compelled-by-fate-accelerated/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2013 18:09:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2013-09-07-compelled-by-fate-accelerated/</guid>
      <description>Summer comes to an end, and I find myself back in the college swing. Which means I’m taking a small break at the moment from REWIRED  after hammering on it the last few months. I’ve been trying to catch back up and see what’s been going on in the RPG communities, and checking out the current big titles these days. Dungeon World and 13th Age pop up a lot in my feeds, and they look real whiz but I can’t justify investing into more fantasy/dungeon crawl games, especially d20 variants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hands On Review – BareBones Fantasy</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2013-05-22-hands-on-review-barebones-fantasy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2013 18:54:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2013-05-22-hands-on-review-barebones-fantasy/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago, I put out a request on G+ to seek out some more Creative Commons licensed tabletop games. From that post, I learned about the upcoming game BareBones Fantasy and was given an opportunity to hop in over G+ Hangouts and try out the system. I have about 3 play sessions under my belt already, have lurked for a few character generation gatherings, have spent time gabbing with Larry Moore (one of BBF’s authors)…and now I have a review copy loaded up on my phone and Nook Color that I’ve been reading over the last couple days.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
