<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>itch on The ChaosGrenade</title>
    <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/tags/itch/</link>
    <description>Recent content in itch on The ChaosGrenade</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 15:50:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://chaosgrenade.com/tags/itch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>SHROOM GOONS Update!</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-09-26-shroom-goons-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 15:50:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-09-26-shroom-goons-update/</guid>
      <description>Some big news regarding SHROOM GOONS!
First off, we got third place in the Goon Jam on Itch.io! Thanks to everyone who’s supported this little title and left amazing feedback and reviews. And to the person who left a 1 star without comment — why do you hate fun?
Second off, there is now an updated SHROOM GOONS available on Itch! Minor edits, small clarifications, expanded Difficulty Scores, and a Referee section that offers some ways to tweak and handle difficult encounters &amp;amp; challenges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SHROOM GOONS — A New Free Title!</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-08-20-shroom-goons-a-new-free-title/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 15:08:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-08-20-shroom-goons-a-new-free-title/</guid>
      <description>SHROOM GOONS is a “Spore-Core” Fantasy Trip for Weird People. A hack of Nate Treme’s Tunnel Goons , players take on the role of tiny mushroom folk on a big adventure! Inspired by Fragglerock, Smurfs, The Littles, Toy Story and other childhood “tiny people” stories. It’s weird, it’s fun, it’s easy to pick up and play. And it features artwork by Skullfungus!
 Arm yourself with a sewing needle sword, a button shield, and ready your matchstick torch!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWESOME D.P.S. — A Free, Narrative-Driven Dice Pool System</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-05-28-awesome-d-p-s-a-free-narrative-driven-dice-pool-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 14:35:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-05-28-awesome-d-p-s-a-free-narrative-driven-dice-pool-system/</guid>
      <description>AWESOME D.P.S. (Dice Pool System) is a fast playing, narrative-driven dice pool RPG framework that is now live on itch.io! as a Pay-What-You-Want Pamphlet RPG.
The goal was to create a game that captures the best part of a dice pool system (grabbing handfuls of dice and feeling like a bad-ass) while minimizing stat blocks and keeping the math simple. Inspired and built off Diogo Nogueira’s Lost in the Fantasy World, these rules were written for gaming sessions that focus more on story and narrative flow than stat crunching or tactical play.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GONZO MUTOID WASTELAND CRUST PUNKS HAS RETURNED!</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-04-08-gonzo-mutoid-wasteland-crust-punks-has-returned/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 15:30:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-04-08-gonzo-mutoid-wasteland-crust-punks-has-returned/</guid>
      <description>The crazy, zany, bat-shit insane post-apocalyptic project that triggered the creation of Drive·10 has now finally glued itself back together! GONZO MUTOID WASTELAND CRUST PUNKS is now available to everyone who pays $2+ to support D·10 on Itch. Inspired by RIFTS, Gamma World, TMNT, Rick &amp;amp; Morty, Adventure Time, Heavy Metal, Super Jail and all sorts of other junk I like, GMWCP is an attempt at a rules-lite game of a fractured reality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DRIVE·10: Now On Itch!</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-03-25-drive10-now-on-itch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 14:49:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-03-25-drive10-now-on-itch/</guid>
      <description>Drive·10, our latest RPG Framework, has been released on Itch.io!
This is an updated and revised version of the original game released last year. There have been a number of tweaks, adjustments, an addition or two, and some necessary editorial passes.
**Drive·10 **is a fast, simple, traditional tabletop role-playing system with easy character creation and streamlined mechanics. Designed for quick pick up and play — brainstorm a setting, make characters, and get to playing all in one evening.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
