<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ChaosGrenade Games on The ChaosGrenade</title>
    <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/categories/chaosgrenade-games/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ChaosGrenade Games on The ChaosGrenade</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 01:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://chaosgrenade.com/categories/chaosgrenade-games/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>INTERMIXX - an RPG Mash-Up</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2022-2-19-intermixx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2022-2-19-intermixx/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;INTERMIXX&lt;/strong&gt; is an &lt;em&gt;RPG Mash-Up&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ndash; a remix of cool ideas and styles to create a fun gaming experience all its own. This is a minimalist, DIY rules set. I assume if you&amp;rsquo;re reading this you&amp;rsquo;re already familiar with role-playing games and how they work. I also assume if you find any rules lacking, you know how to steal ideas from other systems or fill in the blanks yourself. So go grab yourself two six-sided dice, something to write on, and some friends. Think up a setting or genre you want to play. Brainstorm, improvise, and most of all: have fun.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gonzo Mutoids -- Pocket Edition!</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-10-17-gonzo-mutoids-pocket/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-10-17-gonzo-mutoids-pocket/</guid>
      <description>PURCHASE ON ITCH
My love letter to bat-shit crazy, kitchen sink, post apocalyptic settings is now available as a tiny pocket RPG &amp;ndash; this time powered by TRICUBE TALES! All you need is three six-sided dice, some spare tokens and scratch paper.
The base game consists of two tiny booklets (the core game, as well as a bonus GM booklet) that you may print out and fold using the Pocketfold method.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pulling Back the Curtain (on Sigil &amp; Shadow)</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-2-16-pulling-back-the-curtain/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 12:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2021-2-16-pulling-back-the-curtain/</guid>
      <description>Out Now!
Ghosts. Vampires. The monster in your closet. The bogeyman under your bed. The cryptid you read about online. They’re all real. They lurk in our shadows. They linger in our reflections. Good people make pacts with demons they find online. Creatures from beyond time prowl the city streets. Forgotten rituals are reborn as viral memes. The rich and powerful consort with ancient beings behind boardroom doors. Entities beyond our comprehension exploit our desires, gorge themselves on our fears, and manifest as our nightmares.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MAIN SEQUENCE: TRI-FOLD EDITION</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-12-09-main-sequence-tri-fold-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 18:18:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-12-09-main-sequence-tri-fold-edition/</guid>
      <description>What is MAIN SEQUENCE? MAIN SEQUENCE is a fast, “Rules-Necessary” science fiction RPG written by Matt Bryant.
It uses the WyRM System, originally found in titles like Warrior, Rogue &amp;amp; Mage and Resolute, Adventurer &amp;amp; Genius.
MAIN SEQUENCE characters have three Attributes (Soldier, Agent and Tech). They choose a handful of skills and Tags, some equipment, and then they’re off on their planetary adventures! Folks who are wanting a traditional space RPG with a little meat on the bone, but don’t want to be bogged down with bloated catalogs of tech or complex space battles will be at home in MAIN SEQUENCE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SHROOM GOONS — A New Free Title!</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-08-20-shroom-goons-a-new-free-title/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 15:08:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-08-20-shroom-goons-a-new-free-title/</guid>
      <description>SHROOM GOONS is a “Spore-Core” Fantasy Trip for Weird People. A hack of Nate Treme’s Tunnel Goons , players take on the role of tiny mushroom folk on a big adventure! Inspired by Fragglerock, Smurfs, The Littles, Toy Story and other childhood “tiny people” stories. It’s weird, it’s fun, it’s easy to pick up and play. And it features artwork by Skullfungus!
 Arm yourself with a sewing needle sword, a button shield, and ready your matchstick torch!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWESOME D.P.S. — A Free, Narrative-Driven Dice Pool System</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-05-28-awesome-d-p-s-a-free-narrative-driven-dice-pool-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 14:35:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-05-28-awesome-d-p-s-a-free-narrative-driven-dice-pool-system/</guid>
      <description>AWESOME D.P.S. (Dice Pool System) is a fast playing, narrative-driven dice pool RPG framework that is now live on itch.io! as a Pay-What-You-Want Pamphlet RPG.
The goal was to create a game that captures the best part of a dice pool system (grabbing handfuls of dice and feeling like a bad-ass) while minimizing stat blocks and keeping the math simple. Inspired and built off Diogo Nogueira’s Lost in the Fantasy World, these rules were written for gaming sessions that focus more on story and narrative flow than stat crunching or tactical play.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DRIVE·10: Now On Itch!</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-03-25-drive10-now-on-itch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 14:49:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-03-25-drive10-now-on-itch/</guid>
      <description>Drive·10, our latest RPG Framework, has been released on Itch.io!
This is an updated and revised version of the original game released last year. There have been a number of tweaks, adjustments, an addition or two, and some necessary editorial passes.
**Drive·10 **is a fast, simple, traditional tabletop role-playing system with easy character creation and streamlined mechanics. Designed for quick pick up and play — brainstorm a setting, make characters, and get to playing all in one evening.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rota Fortunae: A Simple Fantasy RPG Framework</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2016-04-18-rota-fortunae-a-simple-fantasy-rpg-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2016 04:49:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2016-04-18-rota-fortunae-a-simple-fantasy-rpg-framework/</guid>
      <description>Rota Fortunae is a simple fantasy rpg framework driven by CarPG.
We took the base rules and repackaged it as a complete, stand alone 16-page PDF fantasy game. In addition to showcasing the system in a clean layout, we added all sorts of fun stuff:
 Expanded Skills &amp;amp; Tags A simple magic system with expanded options. 8 fantasy races (plus humans) Additional house-rule options to expand or simplify the game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SIGIL &amp; SHADOW</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/page/sigil-and-shadow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/page/sigil-and-shadow/</guid>
      <description>Welcome! This is a landing page for everything you&amp;rsquo;d need to know about Sigil &amp;amp; Shadow &amp;ndash; a roleplaying game of modern horror, occultism, and fantasy. It is a world where myth, magic, and urban legend collide with our modern post-truth zeitgeist. Players take on the roles of investigators, mystics, occultists, hunters, and monsters, fighting back against the tides of strange and supernatural forces that press against our fragile façade of reality.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
