<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rambling on The ChaosGrenade</title>
    <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/tags/rambling/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rambling on The ChaosGrenade</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 20:46:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://chaosgrenade.com/tags/rambling/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Rambling On: NEUROCITY</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2020-08-13-rambling-on-neurocity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 20:46:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2020-08-13-rambling-on-neurocity/</guid>
      <description>Gavriel Quiroga was really cool to send me a review copy of his game Neurocity,a dystopian nightmare RPG that has recently released following a successful Kickstarter. It’s clocking in at 126 pages for the PDF, although that includes covers, a couple pages of backer names, and a few blanks that I believe are just there for layout purposes.
NEUROCITY was pitched to me as PARANOIA meets Clive Barker, and I feel that is accurate and an understatement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NEON CITY OVERDRIVE</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2020-05-12-neon-city-overdrive/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 15:47:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2020-05-12-neon-city-overdrive/</guid>
      <description>Cut To The Chase Neon City Overdrive is a new cyberpunk rpg put out by Nathan Russell/Peril Planet (creator of Freeform Unlimited), and is available in PDF for $8. From the sales pitch from their DTRPG Listing:
NEON CITY OVERDRIVE is a fast-playing RPG of cyberpunk action. With a focus on story and action, character creation is fast and the rules are intuitive. Create any kind of cyberpunk character you want and throw them into the action within minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RAMBLING ON: TRICUBE TALES</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2020-01-27-rambling-on-tricube-tales/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 19:35:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2020-01-27-rambling-on-tricube-tales/</guid>
      <description>I need to talk about this game, Tricube Tales by Richard Woolcock of Zadmar&amp;rsquo;s Games. There’s a lot I want to say about it, which is crazy because it’s also pretty lite and simple. Also, the damn game is free (full thing in the preview) so you can easily check it for yourself. Yeah, it’s 49 pages, but it’s using that fancy Phone PDF format so it’s really a quick read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting Anarchy</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-05-13-fanstuff-revisiting-anarchy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 21:15:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-05-13-fanstuff-revisiting-anarchy/</guid>
      <description>Shadowrun: Anarchy is a title that I often call a “flawed gem” — a great game marred by poor execution. Rushed edits, a somewhat schizophrenic design (is it a core rulebook? Is it a supplement?), stretching itself thin trying to please both traditional SR veterans and newcomer storygamers. But despite all of that, underneath the rubble you can find the chassis of a slick, streamlined and adaptable dicepool system.
While I’m excited to see where the Sixth World Edition is heading, I find myself slinking back into my copy of Anarchy (goblinized warts and all).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pamphlets, Zines, and Other Fun Things</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-05-02-pamphlets-zines-and-other-fun-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 15:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-05-02-pamphlets-zines-and-other-fun-things/</guid>
      <description>Another spotlight post of cool indie/DIY RPG stuff and other fun things from around the geek webs.
The RPG Pamphlet Craze! Nate Treme (Highland Paranormal Society/ In The Light of a Ghost Star) has made some awesome pamphlet dungeons, and hosted an Pamphlet Dungeon Jam that has resulted in some incredible creations!
I had received hard copies of his Temple of the Bat Serpent and The Mephitic Laboratory of the Pescamancerand was impressed with how much you could put on a standard tri-fold adventure module!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rambling On: Solar Blades &amp; Cosmic Spells</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-03-05-rambling-on-solar-blades-cosmic-spells/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 16:05:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-03-05-rambling-on-solar-blades-cosmic-spells/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been a hell of a wait, but at long last I have Diogo Nogueira’s latest offering: &lt;strong&gt;Solar Blades &amp;amp; Cosmic Spells.&lt;/strong&gt; Built off the same rules as his sword &amp;amp; sorcery offering &lt;em&gt;(Sharp Swords &amp;amp; Sinister Spells),&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;SB&amp;amp;CS&lt;/strong&gt; is more than a science-fantasy re-skin — it is a &lt;em&gt;massive&lt;/em&gt; offering of everything you would want or need for a gonzo, pulpy space adventure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rambling on: In The Light of a Ghost Star</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-01-29-rambling-on-in-the-light-of-a-ghost-star/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 16:59:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-01-29-rambling-on-in-the-light-of-a-ghost-star/</guid>
      <description>Short, sweet, and to the point: **In The Light of a Ghost Star **by Nate Treme of Highland Paranormal Society is a wonderful zine-rpg that is easy to pick up and run after a quick read through. Players take on the role of martian explorers being dropped off on a dead Earth to explore its treacherous ruins filled with strange inhabitants. That’s literally all the story we have, and it’s all that’s really needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rambling on: Vieja Escuela</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-01-20-rambling-on-vieja-escuela/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 18:08:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2019-01-20-rambling-on-vieja-escuela/</guid>
      <description>I’m mad at myself for not blogging about this until now. In the past year or so we’ve seen a lot of cool minimalist and “OSR-Adjacent” D&amp;amp;D clones come out. Black Hack 2e, Untold Adventures, and Knave are a few of the ones I enjoy. But the one that stole the show is a little booklet named Vieja Escuela, a Spanish RPG that had been translated to several languages (including English).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: IRONSWORN</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2018-11-07-review-ironsworn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 15:39:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2018-11-07-review-ironsworn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“In the Ironsworn tabletop roleplaying game, you are a hero sworn to undertake perilous quests in the dark fantasy setting of the Ironlands. You will explore untracked wilds, fight desperate battles, forge bonds with isolated communities, and reveal the secrets of this harsh land. Most importantly, you will swear iron vows and see them fulfilled—no matter the cost.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keep an Eye On: Against the Darkmaster</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2018-07-23-keep-an-eye-on-against-the-darkmaster/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 11:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2018-07-23-keep-an-eye-on-against-the-darkmaster/</guid>
      <description>I am shocked that I’m not seeing any buzz over this awesome upcoming title. Let’s remedy that.
Against the Darkmaster is a game that started out as a clone/house-ruled version of Middle Earth Role-Playing and Rolemaster but has evolved into its own game. The authors list various inspirations from books by Tolkien, Brooks and Goodkind to movies from 70’s and 80’s like Dragonslayer and Krull. They even have an extensive Spotify playlist of heavy metal music and really you should just go look at their God-damned awesome looking website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on High Valor</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2016-11-18-reflections-on-high-valor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 18:29:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2016-11-18-reflections-on-high-valor/</guid>
      <description>Six years ago, I had my view on gaming flipped on its head. I was at the end of a two-year 4e D&amp;amp;D campaign; one that saw decks of power cards, miniatures, three different desktop applications, and combat encounters that lasted entire evenings. It was clear that, while we had a blast, that the days of such bloated systems were in need of ending. We needed something lighter, more elegant, and easier to run in the fewer hours we had.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ramblings on Shadowrun: Anarchy</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2016-10-17-ramblings-on-shadowrun-anarchy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 13:57:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2016-10-17-ramblings-on-shadowrun-anarchy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, it happened.&lt;br&gt;
Catalyst Game Labs released &lt;em&gt;**&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.drivethrurpg.com/product/194759/Shadowrun-Anarchy?hot60=0&amp;amp;src=hnum&#34;&gt;Shadowrun: Anarchy,&lt;/a&gt; **&lt;/em&gt; an “alternate rules set” that aims at letting players run the shadows of the Sixth World in a more story-driven rules set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking for a solid, full review of &lt;em&gt;Anarchy&lt;/em&gt; I highly recommend the &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Casting Shadows review.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;  Otherwise, I’m just going to sit here and gush fanboy for a moment…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[WHITE STAR]: 5 Quick &amp; Dirty Supplement Reviews</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2015-06-15-white-star-5-quick-dirty-supplement-reviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 01:41:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2015-06-15-white-star-5-quick-dirty-supplement-reviews/</guid>
      <description>Today’s post is looking at five different supplements available from RPGNow, each of them no more than a few bucks. I’ve been enjoying the hell out of **White Star. **And one of the solid strengths of it is the amazing community and third-party support that is running with it.
Psionics **Author: **Matthew Skail
**Cost: **$1.99
**Page Count: **11 (including cover and license)
_Psionics _is what it says on the tin: a psionicist class for White Star.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WHITE STAR: A Rambling Review</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2015-05-29-white-star-a-rambling-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2015 05:38:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2015-05-29-white-star-a-rambling-review/</guid>
      <description>I have a curse where every time I say “I don’t need another OSR game!” I open up my wallet and acquire another one.
**White Star **is written by James M. Spahn and released by Barrel Rider Games. The gist of it is they took the rules from Swords &amp;amp; Wizardry Whitebox and hacked it into their own super slick science fiction game. Now, I’m already a rabid fan of Kevin Crawford’s _Stars Without Number, _and I was hesitant to toss $10 at a lighter, simpler game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sneak Peek: COVERT OPS from DwD Studios</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2013-10-29-sneak-peak-covert-ops-from-dwd-studios/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2013 18:11:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2013-10-29-sneak-peak-covert-ops-from-dwd-studios/</guid>
      <description>Today’s post falls on the anniversary of the BareBones Fantasy release. For those who missed out, BBF was a solid percentile based role-playing game that captured the joys and feels of traditional dungeon crawlers and fantasy games, but with very quick-playing rules and fast-paced charts that allowed you to stock your campaign world in a jiffy. (Feel free to recap with my full review.)
After a very successful launch, BBF continued to be supported with a line of equal quality products that included a brush stroked campaign setting, a book of optional races, a few adventures and even a free e-zine with content provided from the community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hands On Review – BareBones Fantasy</title>
      <link>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2013-05-22-hands-on-review-barebones-fantasy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2013 18:54:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chaosgrenade.com/post/2013-05-22-hands-on-review-barebones-fantasy/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago, I put out a request on G+ to seek out some more Creative Commons licensed tabletop games. From that post, I learned about the upcoming game BareBones Fantasy and was given an opportunity to hop in over G+ Hangouts and try out the system. I have about 3 play sessions under my belt already, have lurked for a few character generation gatherings, have spent time gabbing with Larry Moore (one of BBF’s authors)…and now I have a review copy loaded up on my phone and Nook Color that I’ve been reading over the last couple days.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
